Michael Longley papers, 1960-2000
Emory University
- Printed material, 1952-2000, Series 4; Boxes 49-56; OP 8-12
  Organized into three subseries: (4.1) Printed material by Michael Longley, (4.2) Printed material about Michael Longley, and (4.3) General printed material.
  - Printed material by Michael Longley, 1961-2000, Subseries 4.1; Boxes 49-51; OP8
    - "After the Fuss - 'Lady Chatterley'" [article] in Trinity News, 9 May 1961 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - "All of These People" in Irish Times, 26 August 1996 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - "An Artist of the Aftermath" [introduction] in Displaced in Mortal Light (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "Argos" in Times Literary Supplement, 5 April 1991 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - "Baucis & Philemon" in London Review of Books, 17 December 1992 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - "A Bed of Leaves" in The New Yorker, 17 April 1995 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - "Behind a Cloud" in The New Yorker, 25 April 1994 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - "Between Hovers" in The Irish Times, 25 March 1989 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Birds and Flowers [Morning Star Folio 5 / 1], February 1999 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - "Birds and Flowers" in The New Yorker, 19 January 1998 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - "The Branch" in The New Yorker, 2 October 1995 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - "Brian O'Donnell: An Appreciation" [article] [unidentified source], n.d. (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - "Burren Prayer" in The Irish Times, 11 April 1992 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - "Camouflage" in The Irish Times, 5 September 1964 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - "Carrying Flowers out of the Smoke: War Poems" [handout for University of Ulster symposium, 24-26 September 1992] (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - "Ceasefire" in The New Yorker, 15 May 1995 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - "Ceasefire" [two Hungarian translations] in Nagy Világ, July-August 1995 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - "Ceasefire" in The Independent [with misprint], 10 January 1996 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - "Ceasefire" in CA News, December 1996 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - "Ceasefire" in The New Irelander, special election issue 1998 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - "Ceasefire" [Poetry Book Society poster] (Box OP8)
    - "Christmas Decorations" in The Irish Times, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - "Christopher at Birth" in The Irish Times, 12 June 1965 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - "The Comber" in The New Yorker, 23 September 1996 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - "Craft and Vision" [essay] PBS Bulletin 178, Autumn 1998 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - "Crude Pruning will seriously damage tree of knowledge" [letter] in Belfast Telegraph, 9 November 1998 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - "Day Lewis's Virgil" [review of The Eclogues of Virgil by Day Lewis] in The Irish Times, 30 March 1963 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - "Death of a Poet" [review of The Burning Perch by Louis Macneice] in The Irish Times, 14 September 1963 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - "Detour" in The Observer, 24 March 1991 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - "Diving Deep for Victory" [review of Magennis VC by George Fleming; printed with "Ocean"] in The Irish Times, 22 August 1998 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - "Elegies" [handout for reading in Tucson, Arizona, 8 October 1995] (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - "Elegy" [unidentified source, dated 20 May 1997] (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - "An Embattled Celebration" [essay] in PBS Bulletin 184, Spring 2000 (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - "Emlékezés Szülovárosomra" in Nagy Világ, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - "Epithalamion" in Ulster Love Poems, compiled by Michael Longley, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - "Etruria" and "The Blackthorn" [unidentified source], 7 December 1999 (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - "The Excavator" in A Crazy Knot (1996) (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - "The Factory," "Heartsease" and "The Parody" in College Green, August 1999 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - "Featherings" [review of Irish Birds by David Cabot; accompanied by "The Meteorite"] in The Irish Times, 23 December 1995 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - "A Few Thoughts about 'Ghetto'" in West Cork Chamber Music Festival Programme, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - "Five Poets" [reviews of volumes by Plath, Moraes, Crichton Smith, Silkin, Connor] in The Irish Times, 2 October 1965 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - "The Flock" in The New Yorker, 19 February 1996 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - "Font" in The New Yorker, 17 December 1990 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - "Frank O'Connor: An Interview" in Twentieth-Century Literature, Fall 1990 [orig. published 1963] (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - "Freeze-up" in The Irish Times, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - "Foreward" to The Burren by E. Charles Nelson (1997) (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - "Galapagos" and "Remembering Carrigskeewaun" in The Independent, 19-20 November 1998 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Gazeta Forteczna 3 [Polish translations of Michael Longley], circa 1998 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - "Gerald Dillon at the Tom Caldwell Gallery" [article] [unidentified source], n.d. (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - "Ghetto" in The Independent on Sunday, 24 March 1991 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - "Goldcrest" in Christmas card, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - "Headstone" in Gown Literary Supplement, Summer 1993 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - "A Headstone" in The Irish Times, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - "Heimkehr" [Homecoming] in Flugasche, Winter 1992 (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - "Homage to Buster Keaton" and "Klondike" in The Irish Times, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - "The Ice-Cream Man" [unidentified source], n.d. (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - "In a Mississauga Garden" in New Yorker, 18 February 1991 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - "In Memory of Gerard Dillon" in Gerard Dillon: A Retrospective Exhibition, 1972-1973 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - "An Inner Adventure" [essay] in Phoenix, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - "January 12, 1996" and "The Mustard Tin" in London Review of Books, 6 February 1997 (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - "Laertes" in New Yorker, 21 May 1990 (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - "Left Behind" [x2] in The Irish Times, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - "The Level Crossing" in Signals (1997) (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - "The Love Poet" in Patchwork (1981) (Box 50, Folder 27)
    - Lyrikertreffen [German translations of Michael Longley], April 1997 (Box 50, Folder 28)
    - Meet Michael Longley [pamphlet anthology], circa 1984 (Box 50, Folder 29)
    - "Meteorite" in The Irish Times, 23 December 1995 (Box 50, Folder 30)
    - "Michael Longley writes.. ." [x2] [essay] in Poetry Book Society Bulletin 103, Christmas 1979 (Box 50, Folder 31)
    - "Michael Longley writes.. ." [essay] in Poetry Book Society Bulletin 165, Summer 1995 (Box 50, Folder 32)
    - "A Nativity" [multiple imprints], Christmas 1970 (Box 50, Folder 33)
    - "No Man's Land" in The Irish Times, circa 1985 (Box 50, Folder 34)
    - "The Northerner" [essay] in Sunday Independent, 26 September 1976 (Box 50, Folder 35)
    - "'Observe the Sons of Ulster Marching Towards the Somme'" [letter] in The Irish Times, 2 March 1985 (Box 50, Folder 36)
    - "Ocean" in The Irish Times, 22 August 1998 (Box 50, Folder 37)
    - "The Osprey" in New Statesman, 25 December 1964 (Box 50, Folder 38)
    - "Peace" [unidentified source], n.d. (Box 50, Folder 39)
    - "The Pleiades" in memorial pamphlet for Oisín John Ferran, circa 1993 (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - "Ponies" in The Independent, 23 November 1998 (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - "A Poppy" in The Irish Times, 8 November 1997 (Box 50, Folder 42)
    - "Purlin" and "In Ailwee Cave" in Quarto 11, Summer 1991 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - "The Rabbit" in The Irish Times, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - "The Rabbit" in Kwestologo [Arvon publication], November 1998 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - "Recent Poetry" [reviews] in The Irish Times, 27 November 1965 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - "River & Fountain" in The Irish Times, 9 May 1992 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - "River & Fountain" in Hermathena, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - School News, four articles / essays by Michael Longley [one co-authored with P.R. Longley] in magazine of Royal Belfast Academical Institution, dates spanning 1954 - 1959 [also includes early Mahon poem, "Dancehall Impromptu"] (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - "A Ship of the Wind" in Icarus 102, December 1994 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - "The Snow Leopard" in The New Yorker, 10 March 1997 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - "Some Recent Poetry" [reviews] in The Irish Times, circa 1965 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - "Spiderwoman" in The New Yorker, 28 November 1994 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - "Strangford Stone" in Stone and Soil [Royal Mail Millenium Stamps series packet], July 2000 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - "Tu'Penny Stung" in Poetry Review 74.4, January 1985 [and Peter McDonald, "From Ulster with Love"] (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - "Two Peace Poems and a Few Thoughts about them" [essay] in ABEI Newsletter, June 1997 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - "View" [unidentified source], n.d. (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - "The War Graves" in The Observer Review, 9 November 1997 (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - "The War Graves" in The Guardian, 4 March 2000 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - "The Waterfall" in The New Yorker, 14 June 1999 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - "The Weasel's Tooth" [letter] in The Irish Times?, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - "The White Lake" [score, with music by Phillip Hammond; dated 14 August 1999] (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - Printed material about Michael Longley, 1952-2000, Subseries 4.2; Box 52 - Box 54: folders 1-3; OP9-11
    - Reviews - Secret Marriages (1968) (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Reviews - No Continuing City (1969) (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Reviews - An Exploded View (1973) (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Reviews - Man Lying on a Wall (1976) (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Reviews - The Echo Gate (1979) (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Reviews - Selected Poems 1963-1980 (1981) (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Reviews - Patchwork (1981) (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Reviews - Poems, 1963-1983 (1985) (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Reviews - Selected Poems of Louis MacNeice (1988) (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Reviews - Gorse Fires (1991) (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Reviews - The Ghost Orchid (1995) (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Reviews - Selected Poems (1998) (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Reviews - The Weather in Japan (2000) (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Reviews - miscellaneous (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Promotional material - No Continuing City (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Promotional material - Under the Moon, Over the Stars (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Promotional material - The Echo Gate (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Promotional material - Patchwork (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Promotional material - Poems 1963-1983 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Promotional material - Gorse Fires (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Promotional material - The Ghost Orchid (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Promotional material - The Weather in Japan (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Promotional material - various (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - Events involving Michael Longley: 1965-1989 (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Events involving Michael Longley: "Canadian Association for Irish Studies Seventh Annual Seminar: Contemporary Irish Writing" [poster], March 1974 (Box OP9)
    - Events involving Michael Longley: "Michael Longley Reading His Poems, with Commentary" [poster], March 1988 (Box OP10)
    - Events involving Michael Longley: 1992-1995 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Events involving Michael Longley: 1996 (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Events involving Michael Longley: 1997 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Events involving Michael Longley: "An Evening with Michael Longley" [poster], September 1997 (Box OP11)
    - "An Evening with Michael Longley" [poster], September 1997 (Box OP6)
    - Events involving Michael Longley: 1998 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Events involving Michael Longley: 1999-2000 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Events involving Michael Longley: undated (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Clippings about Michael Longley: 1965-1976 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Clippings about Michael Longley: 1983-1995 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Clippings about Michael Longley: 1996-1999 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Clippings about Michael Longley: 2000 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Clippings about Michael Longley: n.d. (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - "Blooming Lately" [interview with Eileen Battersby, orig. from The Irish Times, 9 March 2000] (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - "Four Love Poems and a Note" by Maria Helena Kopschitz in ABEI Newsletter, June 1998 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - "The Future is Behind Us" [interview with Pat Boran] in Books Ireland, Summer 1995 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - "'I hope what I write, no matter how bleak it is, is a celebration'" by Kate Shanahan in Irish Press, 2 December 1991 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - "An Interview with Michael Longley" by Geordie Schimmel in Libertas, 20 February 1997 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - "Making Some Kind of Sense" by Fintan O'Toole in The Sunday Tribune, 17 March 1985 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - "Michael Longley - Biography" by Conor Kelly from <www.local.ie> (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - "Michael Longley: The Interview" by Niall McGrath in Poetry Life, Spring 1996 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - "Michael Longley" by Michael Allen in Contemporary Writers pamphlet [published by British Council], 1993 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - "Michael Longley: Life and Writings" [unidentified source], n.d. (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - "Michael Longley: une grande voix poétique actuelle" in <www.nicematin.fr>, circa 24 December 1999 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - "Michael Longley" in Lyrikertreffen Münster 1997 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - "Of Flock and Fold" by Tom Adair [unidentified source], n.d. (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - "Orange and Green and Read all over" by Raymond Gardner in Arts Guardian, 1 June 1976 (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - "A Poet, And I Know It" by Becky Longley in Belfast Tribune (colour supplement), 1 January 1989 (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - "A Poet for All Seasons" by Nick Miller in Tribune, 15 March 1997 (Box 53, Folder 25)
    - "A poet not without honour in his own country" by Neil Johnstone in Belfast Telegraph, 30 January 1996 (Box 53, Folder 26)
    - "Profile: Michael Longley" in Trinity News, circa 1960s (Box 53, Folder 27)
    - "Taking the Long Route" by Sean O'Brien in Aloud, March 1992 (Box 53, Folder 28)
    - Printed materials concerning Michael Longley's addition to the Leaving Certificate Examination (Box 53, Folder 29)
    - Orders of Service [various, some involving Michael Longley], 1952-2000 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Curriculum vitaes received for Aósdana membership (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Morning Star folios [including Birds & Flowers] (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - General printed material, Subseries 4.3; Box 54: folders 4-8 - Box 56; OP12
    - Hall, Donald, "In November In Advent Waiting" [broadsheet] (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "Heaney Discusses Irish Literary Tradition," Interview by Jack Stuart, The Voice, February 15, 1989 (Box OP12)
    - Heaney, Seamus, "The Poet as a Christian," [photocopy] (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Mahon, Derek, various clippings [includes juvenalia from School News] (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Printed material: literary subjects (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Printed material: literary subjects (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Printed material: literary subjects (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Printed material: literary subjects (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Printed material: literary subjects (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Printed material: literary subjects (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Printed material: literary subjects (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Printed material: Arts (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Printed material: Arts (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Printed material: Miscellaneous (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Printed material: Miscellaneous (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Printed material: Miscellaneous (Box 56, Folder 5)
- Photographs, Series 5; Box 57
  This series contains photographs of Michael Longley, spanning most of his life, although the bulk of the images are from the mid-1980s onwards. There are a few photos of Longley with other literary figures, as well as pictures of various members of his family.
  - Michael Longley and brother as children, 3 photographs (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - "The Gang 1953": Boy Scouts photograph including Michael and Peter Longley (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Michael Longley, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Michael Longley, Seamus Heaney, and David Hammond, n.d. [circa 1965] (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Michael Longley with Young Farmers Club members, 14 March 1975, 2 photographs (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Michael Longley at the Giant's Causeway [taken by Don McPhee], n.d. (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Michael Longley, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Michael Longley and Paul Muldoon at Ulster Musuem, n.d. [circa 1985] (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Michael Longley with (left to right) Gail Walker, Martin Mooney, Patrick Ramsey, Denis Geig, John Kelly, Janet Shepperson, and Kevin Smith, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Michael Longley with others, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Michael Longley at Boston Park Plaza, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Michael Longley, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Michael Longley, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Michael Longley [by Jane Bohr?], 12 March 1991 (Box 57, Folder 14)
  - Michael Longley among tombstones [by Paul McCaffrey], n.d. (2 photographs) (Box 57, Folder 15)
  - Michael Longley with Sophie Allen? and Great Book of Ireland, n.d. [circa early 1990's] (Box 57, Folder 16)
  - Michael Longley, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 17)
  - Michael Longley and others [including Paul Muldoon and John Montague] (Box 57, Folder 18)
  - Michael Longley and Piotr Sommer, contact sheet [Lumb Bank, June 1998] (Box 57, Folder 19)
  - Photograph of Pete Edwards' portrait of Michael Longley, October 1989 (Box 57, Folder 20)
  - Michael Longley [3 contact sheets], n.d. (Box 57, Folder 21)
  - Michael Longley, various printed copies of photographs under consideration for The Poetry of Michael Longley, ed. Peacock (Box 57, Folder 22)
  - Edna Longley (3 photographs) (Box 57, Folder 23)
  - Michael Longley's father in WW I (5 photographs) (Box 57, Folder 24)
  - Michael Longley's grandmother (Box 57, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous family photographs (Box 57, Folder 26)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 57, Folder 27)
- Financial records, Series 6; Box 58
  Contracts and royalty statements for a number of Michael Longley's published works can be found in this series, as well as financial papers related to some of his work for the BBC.
  - No Continuing City, contract (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - An Exploded View, contract and royalty statements (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Man Lying on a Wall, contract (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Penguin Modern Poets, royalty statements (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Poems, 1963-1983, contracts (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Gorse Fires, contract (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Selected Poems (1998), contract (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - The Weather in Japan, contract (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - BBC broadcasts, financial papers (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - BBC broadcasts, W.B. Yeats film--financial papers (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous financial documents (Box 58, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous personal files, Series 7; Box 59; OP13
  This series contains various materials which have relevance to Michael Longley's personal life, including drafts of curriculum vitae, details of prizes won, and ephemera by his children.
  - Curriculum vitae and biographical material (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Longley family genealogy (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Pencil drawing of Michael Longley by Robert McGuinness (Box OP13)
  - Prizes and awards (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Prizes and awards, Whitbread Book of the Year, 1991 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Sketches and water colors (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous material related to Michael Longley and family (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Materials regarding Michael Longley's children (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous addresses and non-literary notes (Box 59, Folder 8)
- Belfast Group sheets, Series 8; Box 60
  In the early 1960s, the poet Philip Hobsbaum founded in Belfast an informal writers' group where the participants could read and discuss each other's work. Poems and, in some cases, short stories that were being presented at these meetings were customarily mimeographed and distributed to those attending. These "group sheets" make up a distinct series, and include early work by Seamus Heaney, Derek Mahon, Paul Muldoon, and Michael Longley, among others.
  Related Collections in this Repository
  Belfast Group sheets may also be found in the Irish Literary Miscellany.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by author.
  - Dugdale, Norman: "Terminus," "A Question of Identity," A Self-Portrait," "Salmon-Leaf: Mayo," "On a Recent Happy Event," "Saturday," "N.W.S," "Autopsy on the Fifth Decade" [2 copies] (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Harvey, W.J.: "The Poem in October," "Reading Drayton in October," "Hart Crane," "Sea-Side Song," "Leni Riefenstahl's Olympiad: 1936," "The Sorcerer's Apprentice," "Arriving at Larne: Seasick" (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Heaney, Seamus, April 27, 1965: "Boy Driving his Father to Confession," "To A Wine Jar," "On Hogarth's Engraving 'Pit Ticket for the Royal Sport'," "Synge on Aran," "Blackberry-Picking," "Saint Francis and the Birds," "At a Potato Digging" (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Heaney, Seamus: "Icon," "Limbo," Wedding Day," The Last Mummer," "High Street, Belfast, 1786," "Tweed," "Dawn," "Bye-Child" (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Heaney, Seamus: "Digging," "Death of a Naturalist," "Storm on the Island," "Soliloquy for an Old Resident," "Writer and Teacher," "Young Batchelor," "Scaffolding" [2 copies] (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Heaney, Seamus: A Lough Neagh Sequence ["1. Vision," "2. The Coming," "3. Bait," "4. Setting," "5. Lifting," "6. The Going," "7. Coda"] [2 copies] (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Heaney, Seamus: "At Ardboe Point," "Good-Night," "The Crowing Man," "Shore Woman," "Yank," "A Winter's Tale" (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Heaney, Seamus: "The Diviner," "Gravities," "Ancestral Photograph," "For the Commander of 'The Eliza'," "Personal Helicon," "Girls Bathing, Galway, 1965," "The Salmon Fisher to the Salmon" [3 copies, 1 with holograph notes] (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Heaney, Seamus: "Elegy for an Unborn Child," "Tritych for the Eater Battlers," "Hamge to Pieter Breughel," "Persephone," "Rookery," "Requiem for the Irish Rebels," "The Peninsula," "Orange Drums, Tyrone 1966" [2 copies, 1 with holograph notes] (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Heaney, Seamus, Michael Longley, and Brendan Kennelly: "Death of a Naturalist," "Lovers on Aran," "Follower," "Elegy for a Still-Born Child," "Personal Helicon," "Antaeus," "The After-Child," "The Blind Man," "Marlowe," "The Good," "Light Dying," The Dummies," "The Osprey," "The Hebrides," "Elegy for Fats Waller," "Dr Johnson Dying," "Gathering Mushrooms," "Persephone" (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Longley, Michael: "A Headstone," "Man Friday," "Out of the Sea" ["1. Seahorses," "2. Bikini Atoll"], "Homage to Buster Keaton," "Fanny Hill," "Klondike," "Journey out of Essex," "Barracuda" [6 copies, 3 with holograph notes] (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Longley, Michael: "Circe," "The Ornithological Section," "Orpheus," "A Personal Statement," "The Centaurs," "The Housewife's Testament," "Christopher at Birth" [3 copies, 1 with holograph notes] (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Longley, Michael: "Althera Cithera," "Three Posthumous Pieces," "The Island," "Casualty," "Badger," "Hedgehog," "Kingfisher," "Robin," "The Adulterer" [3 copies] (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - Longley, Michael: "Emily Dickinson," "The Osprey," "In Memoriam," "Christopher at Birth," "Gathering Mushrooms," "Persephone," "Dr. Johnson on the Hebrides," "Remembrance Day," "Man Friday" (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Longley, Michael: "Dr. Johnson on the Hebrides," "Leaving Inishmore," "Camouflage," "Persephone," "To Derek Mahon," "A Working Holiday," "Words for Jazz Perhaps" ["1. Elegy for Fats Waller," "2. Billie Holiday," "3. Bud Freeman in Belfast," "4. To Bessie Smith"] (Box 60, Folder 15)
  - Longley, Michael: "No Continuing City," "A Slight Adultery," "The Journey," "To Edna," "Her Mime of the Lame Seagull," "The Hebrides" [with holograph corrections] (Box 60, Folder 16)